## Ahmad Luqman

Islamabad, Pakistan

 $+92-300-5560154 \bullet ahmad.luqman@gmail.com \bullet http://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmadluqman \bullet https://github.com/ahmad-luqman/ \bullet https://stackoverflow.com/users/713683/luqi$ 

#### About

A software architect with passion of building great products by building culture of continuous improvement in people, process and products to enable continuous delivery of values to end users. I have worked as a software engineer with 2 decades of experience developing softwares.

### WORK HISTORY

## CreditPer, Islamabad (Feb 2022 - Jan 2023) Head Of Engineering

- Responsible for hiring, managing engineering of 15+ engineering team compromising of Full Stack, Frontend, QA, Data Science, Project Management and Product Management.
- Handling solution architecture by monitoring and improving the performance of the system by observing the logs and performance monitoring tools.
- Technologies used are React, Nodejs, React Native and Python deployed on AWS.

#### EMPG labs, Islamabad (July 2020 - Dec 2021)

#### $Software\ Architect$

- Responsible for engineering execution of softwares for CRM related to real estate transactional business.
- Responsible for managing team of 38 engineers and involved in hiring onboarding process and scaling from 10 to 38 team count
- Technologies used are Angular, Nodejs, React Native deployed on AWS.

## Breu Inc., Remote Work (Dec 2019 - June 2020)

### VP of Engineering

- Responsible for all aspects of software development and engineering delivery
- Architect and develop a product around TWAMP protocol with clients written in Rust and backend in Python Django hosted as containers on AWS with Angular
- Technologies used are Angular, Python, Django, AWS, Terraform, Rust

## $\mathbf{LMKR}$ , $\mathbf{Islamabad}$ (March 2011 - Nov 2019)

#### Development Lead Platform, R&D

- Leading a Architecture and Configuration Management team responsible for setting up CI and daily builds and making desktop installers available to the respective teams.
- Job responsibilities include developing and architecting application, mentoring developers, doing code reviews, conducting technical interviews for hiring.
- Currently working with 3d visualization team maintaining and developing a product using C#, WPF, SlimDX, DirectX 11 technologies.
- $\bullet$  Contributed towards LMKR SDK for accessing Geographix database for well survey data using C# and EF 5.0 and also helped in Well Planner application integration with smartSECTION
- Worked with Geology team and developing & maintaining their products used for Oil & Gas geological log interpretation workflows, improved performance of applications by parallelizing User Defined Equations calculation for PRIZM<sup>TM</sup> using C++ PPL
- Developed a XS2SS file format convertor utility in C#, WPF with MVVM architecture and more than 80% code coverage through unit tests.
- Worked on Volume Attributes team, a geophysical attributes calculator for seismic data interpretation in C# 4.0 utilizing TPL to parallelize processing. Also developed the UI in WPF.

## Bentley Systems, inc. (Trivor Software was acquired by Bentley Systems, inc. in May 2007.), Islamabad (May 2007 - Feb 2011)

### Senior Software Engineer/Team Lead

- Worked on AutoPlant Core team and developed an offline ProjectWise (Bentley DMS product) project support for AutoPlant projects using C++/VB for legacy code and .Net C# for newer modules. This was part of a Bentley AutoPlant XM 8.9.4 release. (March 2007 August 2007)
- Worked on Platform Technology development group developing core Engineering Content Framework (ECFramework) used across multiple Bentley products being developed in .Net C# and Windows Forms and contributed towards one major and two minor releases of V8i. (September 2007 Feb 2011)
- Developed & maintained Bentley Class Editor (Schema editing tool) for defining and editing schemas used across different applications across all Bentley verticals.
- Designed & developed Engineering Units, ECSchema localization & ECSchema Evolution for the ECFramework.
- Worked as a scrum master of one of team
- Introduced Software Engineering Line Engineering concept in the organization

#### Trivor Software (Exclusive Contractors for Bentley Systems, inc.), Islamabad (May 2005 - May 2007) $MIS\ Manager$

- Worked as a MIS Manager (Manager Management of Information Systems) in Trivor Software for six months.
- Worked as a Software Engineer and successfully completed and developed an Engineering based project 'BC PumpPlots' for Brown and Caldwell. BC PumpPlots is an analysis tool for designing Pumping stations.
   (May 2005 Feb 2007)

#### LMKR, IT Services, Islamabad (May 2004 - April 2005) System Administrator

- Responsibility includes management of different services on Linux and Windows environment.
- Common tasks include management of Active Directory, FTP, RAS, DHCP, Citrix Server, squid proxy, DNS and backup of servers.
- Worked on the design and implementation of the new services like GPOs, SMS, SFU, DHCP and DFS.
- Also worked on documenting the policies and procedures of the department for ISO-9000 Certification.

## GIK Institute, Faculty of Electronic Engineering, Topi (May 2003 - May 2004) $Electronic\ Engineer$

- Assisted Image processing course, Conducted labs for Digital logic design, Computer networks and Image processing courses.
- Developed an application in C++ for reading data from a centrifugal machine in Materials Engineering Faculty's lab from its COM Serial port and saving it in .csv file so that data could be plotted in Microsoft Excel.
- As a system administrator was responsible for maintaining the network of the faculty and computer labs.
- Assisted a graduate student in his thesis work for developing linux kernel modules for system call based anomaly intrusion detection system

## ${\bf Advanced\ Engineering\ Research\ Organization,\ Islamabad\ ({\bf summer\ 2002})} \\ {\bf Internee}$

- Worked on video tracking system project using C++ and OpenGL 1.1 and was continued as a final year project for bachelors degree
- Configured a redhat based linux server running sendmail, squid based proxy and software router

# ${\bf Advanced~Engineering~Research~Organization,~Islamabad~(summer~2001)} \\ \underline{{\bf Internee}}$

• Developed and ported a framework for secure VOIP solution to PC on which different encryption protocols and audio encoding protocols could be tested.

### EDUCATION

GIK Institute Topi, Pakistan • Bachelor of Science in Computer Systems Engineering, 2003

• Selected Coursework:

 $\label{lem:computer Science Unix Programming · Data Structures · Automata & Computation · Computer System Fundamentals · Computer Networks · Operating Systems · Algorithms · Object Oriented Systems · Image Processing · Artificial Intelligence · Databases$ 

 $\textbf{Mathematics} \ \, \textbf{Calculus} \cdot \textbf{Differential} \ \, \textbf{Equations} \cdot \textbf{Discrete} \ \, \textbf{Mathematics} \cdot \textbf{Numerical} \ \, \textbf{Analysis}$ 

#### MOOC Courses Udacity, Edx, Coursera • 2013 - To date

• Selected Coursework:

Software Engineering for Software as a Service · Ruby on Rails Heroku Agile Development

CS184.1x Foundation of Computer Graphics - Nov 2013 OpenGL C++

Startup Engineering - June 2013 HTML CSS Javascript NodeJs on AWS

Introduction to Data Science - June 2013 SQL NoSQL Map Reduce Machine Learning

MITx: 15.390x Entrepreneurship 101: Who is your customer? - May 2014

Stanford University - Algorithms: Design and Analysis, Part 1 - July 2014

React Nanodegree program - May 2019 React Redux ReactNative

- Programming Languages: C/C++, C#, Javascript, Typescript, Python, Rust, LATEX
- Frameworks: WPF, WPF, Django, Express, NestJS, React, Angular
- Databases: MySQL, Redis, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQL Server, Sybase SQL Anywhere
- DirectX 11, HLSL, OpenGL
- CI/CD: Azure DevOps, Gitlab CI/CD, Circle CI, Github Actions, ArgoCD
- AWS: EC2, S3, Route53, Cloudfront, IAM, VPC, RDS, Cloudwatch, Lambda
- Containers, Kubernetes, EKS, Helm
- Observability: Cloudwatch, Kibana, NewRelic, Sentry, Firebase
- IAAC: Terraform, Chef, Puppet, Vagrant

#### Talks & Guest Lectures

- Open Source tools & Devops at Open Source Summit 2019 on 3rd Octeber, 2019 at FAST-NU, Islamabad
- State of DevOps at IEEE INMIC 2019 on 30th November, 2019 at FAST-NU, Islamabad
- Infrastructure as Code at DevOps Day with Testers on 8th February, 2020 at VisionX Technologies, Islamabad
- DevOps Introduction on March 2, 2020 at NUST SEECS, Islamabad
- Infrastructure as Code as guest lecture for Cloud Computing course on March 23, 2020 at FAST-NU, Islamabad

#### OPENSOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

- Member of .Net Foundation
- Contributed to dotnet cli project which is now merged to dotnet sdk monorepo
- Minor contributions to Tellform and ThisDevelopersLife-Transcripts projects
- Top 20% on stackoverflow